Guide to the Edmund White Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Edmund White Papers
1905-2013
YCAL MSS 808
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
78.81
(96 boxes)
Includes personal and professional correspondence, manuscripts, research files, biographical material, financial papers, photographs, slides, audio visual material, ephemera.
White, Edmund, 1940-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired primarily from Edmund White by gift and purchase, 1991-2013.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 25, 34, 38, 41, 53, 61, 64, 80-81, and 96 (audiovisual materials): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 54, 73, 82 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Edmund White (1940- )
Edmund White (1940- ), American author.
Scope and Contents
The Edmund White Papers provide insight into the professional and personal life of Edmund White, an American novelist, memoirist, and essayist, and are comprised of correspondence, drafts of writings, research files, personal papers, financial papers, photographs, slides, audiovisual material, computer media, and ephemera.
Arrangement
Organized into twenty-five groupings: I. July 1991 Acquisition. II. September 1991 Acquisition. III. May 1993 Acquisition. IV. August 1993 Acquisition. V. August 1993 Acquisition. VI. June 1994 Acquisition. VII. September 1994 Acquisition. VIII. December 1994 Acquisition. IX. April 1995 Acquisition. X. May 1995 Acquisition. XI. June 1995 Acquisition. XII. November 1995 Acquisition. XIII. December 1996 Acquisition. XIX. January 1997 Acquisition. XV. October 1998 Acquisition. XVI. October 1998 Acquisition. XVII. April 2001 Acquisition. XVIII. November 2001 Acquisition. XIX. September 2003 Acquisition. XX. December 2004 Acquisition. XXI. April 2005 Acquisition. XXII. December 2006 Acquisition. XXIII. November 2007 Acquisition. XXIV. January 2011 Acquisition. XXV. November 2013 Acquisition.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiocassettes -- United States -- 20th Century; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Born digital; Negatives (photographic) -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographic prints -- United States -- 20th Century; Videocassettes -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; LGBTQ resource; Corn, Alfred, 1943-; Cox, Christopher, 1949-1990; McClatchy, J. D., 1945-; Merrill, James, 1926-1995; White, Edmund, 1940-
- July 1991 Acquisition, Series I; 24.92; (27 boxes)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from Edmund White on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1991.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, contains alphabetically arranged correspondence, including a number of folders of letters from Delilah White. Other major correspondents include Alfred Corn, Christopher Cox, David Kalstone, Stanley Redfern, and Marilyn Schaefer.
  Series II, Writings, is contained in Boxes 3-19 and arranged alphabetically by title. It includes manuscripts and typescripts for The Beautiful Room is Empty, A Boy's Own Story, and Nocturne for the King of Naples, as well as manuscripts for several unpublished early works, among them "Private Disquisitions" and "An Amorous History of Youth." There are also manuscripts, typescripts and printed copies of many shorter works, articles, and reviews by White, as well as extensive research files for States of Desire.
  Series III, Financial Papers, fills Boxes 20-22 and contains cancelled checks, checkbooks, tax returns, and various bills and receipts. Box 23 houses Series IV, Clippings, which is divided into two sections: "Interviews" and "Clippings about Edmund White." Series V, Personal Papers, contains two folders of juvenilia, a diary, school papers, awards and memorabilia. Photographs, Series VI, contains portraits of Edmund White, his family, and friends, and includes a Robert Mapplethorpe photograph of White with Truman Capote. Oversize material is located in Boxes 26-29.
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 240.
  Arrangement
  Organized into six series: Correspondence, Writings, Financial Papers, Clippings, Personal Papers, and Photographs.
  - Correspondence, 1905-90
    Series I, Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by author. Unidentified correspondence is found at the end of the series.
    - "A" general, 1977-1982 (Box 1)
    - Altman, Dennis, 1979-1991 (Box 1)
    - "Andrew", 1978 November 10 (Box 1)
    - Ashbery, John, 1972 July 14 (Box 1)
    - "B" general, 1974-1989, undated (Box 1)
    - Barbedette, Gilles, 1980-1982, undated (Box 1)
    - Bartlett, Neil, 1988, undated (Box 1)
    - Bernstein, Leonard, undated (Box 1)
    - Booth, Simon, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
    - Brainard, Joe, 1978-1981, undated; 2 (Box 1)
    - Brann-Hainett Agency, 1970-1979 (Box 1)
    - Burch, Charles and Pat, 1970-1987 (Box 1)
    - "C" general, 1973-1988, undated (Box 1)
    - Corn, Alfred, 1970-1988, undated (Box 1)
    - Corn, Alfred and Ann Jones, 1967-1971 (Box 1)
    - Cox, Christopher, 1978 (Box 1)
    - "D" general, 1970-1988, undated (Box 1)
    - Dowell, Coleman, 1979, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Dureau, George, undated (Box 1)
    - "E" general, 1979-1988, undated (Box 1)
    - Enigenberg, Chad, 1981 (Box 1)
    - "F" general, 1973-1989, undated (Box 1)
    - Fleming, Keith, undated (Box 1)
    - Fleming, Margaret, 1970, undated (Box 1)
    - Foucault, Michel, 1981 (Box 1)
    - "G" general, 1969-1989, undated (Box 1)
    - Garber, Eric (Andrew Holleran), 1979 (Box 1)
    - Gluck, Robert, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Grey, John, 1969-1980, undated; 2 (Box 1)
    - "H" general, 1960-1990, undated (Box 1)
    - Howard, Richard, undated (Box 1)
    - "I" general, 1977-1989 (Box 1)
    - "J" general, 1969-1987 (Box 1)
    - John Wiley and Sons, Inc., 1975-1977 (Box 1)
    - "Julie", 1959, undated (Box 1)
    - "K" general, 1955-1989, undated (Box 1)
    - Kalstone, David, 1971-1981, undated; 2 (Box 1)
    - Karlinsky, Simon, 1973-1988, undated; 3 (Box 1)
    - Kaye, Richard, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Kiley, William, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Klappert, Peter, 1973-1887 (Box 1)
    - Kramer, Larry, 1978 September 11 (Box 1)
    - "L" general, 1975-1989, undated (Box 1)
    - "M" general, 1971-1990, undated (Box 1)
    - McClatchy, J. D., 1977-1989, undated (Box 1)
    - McDermott, Keith, 1978-1979, undated (Box 1)
    - Merrill, James (and David Jackson), 1973-1989 (Box 1)
    - Mortimer, Penelope, 1973-1988 (Box 1)
    - "N" general, 1977-1989, undated (Box 2)
    - Nabokov, Vladimir, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - "O" general, 1980-1989, undated (Box 2)
    - "P" general, 1976-1989, undated (Box 2)
    - Picano, Felice, 1979-1988, undated (Box 2)
    - Pounder, Robert, 1979 (Box 2)
    - Preston, John, 1980, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Purcell, John, 1983-1988, undated (Box 2)
    - "Q" general, 1978 (Box 2)
    - "R" general, 1970-1989, undated (Box 2)
    - Redfern, Stanley, 1970-1985; 2 (Box 2)
    - Ritterbush, Philip, 1979 (Box 2)
    - Rorem, Ned, 1979, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Ruddy, Jim, 1979, undated (Box 2)
    - "S" general, 1979-1989, undated (Box 2)
    - Schaefer, Marilyn, 1961-1983, undated; 2 (Box 2)
    - Scott, Lawrence, 1961 (Box 2)
    - Stambolian, George, 1986-1988 (Box 2)
    - "Steve", undated (Box 2)
    - Stroud, Drew, 1980, undated (Box 2)
    - "T" general, 1978-1981 (Box 2)
    - Torrespico, Laura, 1977-1981, undated (Box 2)
    - "V" general, 1978-1988, undated (Box 2)
    - Vidal, Gore, 1978 (Box 2)
    - "W" general, 1973-1988, undated (Box 2)
    - Waters, John, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Welles, Paul O' M., 1979 (Box 2)
    - White, Delilah, 1958-1990, undated; 22 (Box 2)
    - White, Edmund V. [father], 1962-1979 (Box 2)
    - Whitmore, George, 1977-1980, undated (Box 2)
    - "X" - "Z" general, 1979-1982 (Box 2)
    - Unidentified, 1905, 1970-1990, undated; 3 (Box 2)
  - Writings, 1950-92
    Series II, Writings, is arranged alphabetically by title with the exception of Reviews. Each title is identified by type of material.
    - Writings by Edmund White
      - "Afterword" written for Delilah: A Life in Progress by Delilah White, essay, 1981 (Box 3)
      - "A propos Philip Taaffe": Parkett 26, article, 1990 (Box 3)
      - "The Americanization of Proust": Vogue, article, 1984 November (Box 3)
      - "Amman of Style": Vanity Fair, article, 1988 January (Box 3)
      - The Amorous History of Our Youth: novel
        - Notes: holograph, undated (Box 3)
        - Typescript, undated (Box 3)
        - Typescript, carbon, undated (Box 3)
        - Fragment, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 3)
        - "The Double Session": typescript, undated (Box 3)
      - The Amorous History of the Gauls: musical
        - Outline, undated (Box 3)
        - Typescript, 1961 (Box 3)
      - "Andy Warhol": article, holograph, undated (Box 3)
      - "Andy Warhol: Repro Man": Savvy Woman, article, 1989 October (Box 3)
      - "Anita Brookner's Brief Lives ": article, holograph, undated (Box 3)
      - Argument for a Myth: play
        - Typescript, photocopy, undated (Box 3)
        - Mimeograph, undated (Box 3)
        - Copyright, 1963 October 14 (Box 3)
      - "Arthur Fiedler": Time-Life Records article, 1977 (Box 3)
      - "Aspects of Sexuality": essay, holograph, undated (Box 3)
      - Autobiography
        - Notes: holograph, undated (Box 3)
        - Holograph, undated (Box 3)
      - "Azzedine's Forbidden City": article typescript, undated (Box 3)
      - "Back to Mackinae": HG, article, 1990 June (Box 3)
      - "Basso Ostinato": short story, holograph, undated (Box 3)
      - "Beating the Hot Seat": Saturday Review, article, 1973 (Box 3)
      - The Beautiful Room is Empty [Version I]
        - Outline, holograph, 1966? (Box 3)
        - Outline, typescript, 1967 January 4 (Box 3)
        - Notes, holograph, 1966-1967; 6 (Box 3)
        - Chapter I, Part 1, holograph, undated (Box 3)
        - Chapter I, Part 2, holograph, undated (Box 3)
        - Chapter I, Part 3, holograph, undated (Box 3)
        - Chapter II, Part 1, holograph, undated (Box 3)
        - Chapter II, Part 2, holograph, undated (Box 3)
        - Chapter II, Part 3; Chapter III, Part I, holograph, undated (Box 3)
        - Chapters IV, V, holograph, undated (Box 3)
        - Chapter VI, Part 1, holograph, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapter VI, Part 2, holograph, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapter VI, Part 3, holograph, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapter VII, Part 1, holograph, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapter VII, Part 2, holograph, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapter VII, Part 3, holograph, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapter VII, holograph, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapter I, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapters I-V, typescript, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapters VI-VII, typescript, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapter VIII, typescript, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapters I-III, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapter IV-V, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapter VI, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapter VII, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapter VIII, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 4)
      - "The Beautiful Room is Empty": short story, The Other Persuasion, 1977 (Box 4)
      - [ The Beautiful Room is Empty ]: play, typescript, undated (Box 4)
      - The Beautiful Room is Empty, Version II
        - Notes, holograph, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapter I, Part 1, holograph, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapter I, Part 2, holograph, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapter II, holograph, undated (Box 4)
        - Chapter III, holograph, undated (Box 5)
        - Chapter IV, Part 1, holograph, undated (Box 5)
        - Chapter IV, Part 2, holograph, undated (Box 5)
        - Chapter V, Part 1, holograph, undated (Box 5)
        - Chapter V, Part 2, holograph, undated (Box 5)
        - Chapter VI, holograph, undated (Box 5)
        - Chapters VI-VII, holograph, undated (Box 5)
        - Chapter VIII, holograph, undated (Box 5)
        - Chapters I-III, typescript, 1988 (Box 5)
        - Chapters IV-V, typescript, 1988 (Box 5)
        - Chapters VI-VIII, typescript, 1988 (Box 5)
        - Chapter VII, typescript, undated (Box 5)
        - Chapters I-II, typescript, undated (Box 5)
        - Chapters III-IV, typescript, undated (Box 5)
        - Chapters V-VI, typescript, undated (Box 5)
        - Chapters VII-X, typescript, undated (Box 5)
        - Agreement, 1986 January 13 (Box 5)
        - French translation: notes, holograph, undated (Box 5)
        - Publicity, undated (Box 5)
        - Reviews, 1988; 3 (Box 5)
      - "Beech Lane": short story
        - Notes, holograph, undated (Box 5)
        - Typescript, undated (Box 5)
      - "Before the Revolution": Premiere article, 1989 January (Box 5)
      - "Berlin: Bright Lights, Black Leather": Vogue, article, 1985 October (Box 5)
      - "Billy Boy": article, typescript, undated (Box 5)
      - Blue Boy in Black
        - Outline, holograph, 1961 (Box 5)
        - Typescript, undated (Box 5)
        - Memorabilia, 1961 (Box 5)
        - Copyright, 1962 July 13 (Box 5)
      - A Boy's Own Story
        - Notes, holograph, undated (Box 5)
        - Holograph, undated; 2 (Box 5)
        - Holograph, undated; 5 (Box 6)
        - Typescript, corrected, undated; 3 (Box 6)
        - Setting typescript, with corrections, 1982; 3 (Box 6)
        - Contract, 1981 July 27 (Box 6)
        - French translation with holograph corrections, Samourai, 1982 January (Box 6)
        - Reviews, 1982-1984; 5 (Box 6)
      - "Brahms and His Music": Great Men of Music, article, 1975 (Box 6)
      - "Byzantium's Hour": short story, typescript, undated (Box 6)
      - Caracole: novel
        - Notes, holograph, undated; 3 (Box 6)
        - Notes, typescript, undated (Box 6)
        - Chapter 1, holograph, undated; 3 (Box 6)
        - Part II, holograph, undated; 2 (Box 6)
        - Part II, holograph, undated; 8 (Box 7)
        - Typescript, photocopy, undated; 4 (Box 7)
        - Setting typescript, 1985; 4 (Box 7)
        - Chapter IV, setting typescript, 1985 (Box 7)
        - Contract, 1983 January 24 (Box 7)
        - Publicity, undated (Box 7)
        - French translation proofs: copy, corrected, 1986 (Box 7)
      - Caracole: reviews, 1985-1986; 3 (Box 8)
      - "The Chinese Landscape": article, Horizon, 1975 Autumn (Box 8)
      - "Christopher Isherwood: Down Here on a Visit": New York Native, article, 1986 April 21 (Box 8)
      - Cipriana: play, holograph, 1970 (Box 8)
      - "Cocteau: the Great Enchanter": Vogue, article, 1984 May (Box 8)
      - "Colloquy by the Fire": short story, holograph, undated (Box 8)
      - "Colombe Pringle": article, typescript, 1988 October 10 (Box 8)
      - "Contemporary Gay Culture" article, typescript carbon, undated (Box 8)
      - "The Court of Saint Joan": short story, typescript, undated (Box 8)
      - A Crop of Pins and Pearls: poems, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 8)
      - "Danilo Kis": article, Southwest Review, undated (Box 8)
      - "Danilo Kis: the Obligations of Form": typescript, article, undated (Box 8)
      - Dark Currents: novel
        - Vol. I, holograph, 1955 (Box 8)
        - Vol. II, holograph, 1955 (Box 8)
        - Typescript, 1955 (Box 8)
        - Typescript, carbon [3 copies], 1955; 3 (Box 8)
      - The Darker Proof: book
        "Palace Days"
        - Part 1: holograph, undated (Box 8)
        - Part 2: holograph, undated (Box 8)
        - "Skinned Alive": holograph, undated (Box 8)
        - Uncorrected advance proofs, 1987 (Box 8)
        - Reviews, 1987-1988 (Box 8)
      - "Delinquent Beauty": article, Condé Nast Traveller, 1990 January (Box 8)
      - "Discussion of a Rubbing of the Wu-Linng -Tz'u Shrine: essay, typescript, 1961 December 12 (Box 8)
      - "Diva Mexicana": article, Vogue, 1990 November (Box 8)
      - The Duet: novel
        - Typescript, undated (Box 8)
        - Typescript, carbon, undated (Box 8)
      - "An Emperor of the Mind: Foucault": Vogue, article, 1984 November (Box 8)
      - "The Emptiness of Meaning": essay, typescript, undated (Box 8)
      - "Esthetics and Loss": Artforum, essay, 1987 January (Box 8)
      - "The Esthetics of Bliss": The Saturday Review, essay, undated (Box 8)
      - "Evening for Isherwood": play, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 8)
      - "The Evolution of Edmund White": San Francisco Examiner, article, 1989 June 25 (Box 8)
      - "The Extra-Philosophical Significance of Chu Hsi's Metaphysical and Ethical System": essay, typescript, undated (Box 8)
      - "Fantasia on the Seventies": essay, Christopher Street, 1977 September (Box 8)
      - "First Love": short story, Christopher Street, 1980 March (Box 8)
      - Fixed Point: play, typescript, photocopy, 1963 October (Box 8)
      - Forgetting Elena: novel
        - Setting typescript, 1972; 2 (Box 8)
        - Galleys, with holograph corrections, 1972 (Box 8)
        - Galleys, 1972 (Box 9)
        - Reviews, 1973-74 (Box 9)
        - Royalty statements, 1973-1974 (Box 9)
      - "Forms of Society and Government in Traditional Asia": essay, typescript, undated (Box 9)
      - "Friendship": essay, mimeograph, undated (Box 9)
      - "Gay Fiction Writers": lecture, typescript, photocopy, 1989 May 18 (Box 9)
      - "The Gay Philosopher," essay, typescript, photocopy, [1971?] (Box 9)
      - "Gay S & M, A Closet Drama": essay, typescript, photocopy, 1978 (Box 9)
      - "Gay Story Project": typescript, notes, 1989 January 1 (Box 9)
      - "Gay Writers in France": The Advocate, article, 1987 March 17 (Box 9)
      - "Gay Writers in Paris": The European Gay Review, article, 1986 (Box 9)
      - "George Whitmore": The Advocate, article, 1980 June 12 (Box 9)
      - "Grand Allusions": Vogue, article, 1988 October (Box 9)
      - Harlequin: play, holograph, [1961?] (Box 9)
      - "Henry James's 'Four Meetings'": essay, typescript, 1960 March 18 (Box 9)
      - "The Hermaphrodite": short story, typescript, undated (Box 9)
      - The Hermaphrodite: musical, typescript, 1975; 2 (Box 9)
      - Highgate Farm: play, holograph, 1959 (Box 9)
      - "L'Ile St. Louis": Departures, article, 1988 September-October (Box 9)
      - "International Books of the Year": TLS, 1988 December 2-8 (Box 9)
      - Interview: typescript, undated (Box 9)
      - "An Interview with Edmund White by Christopher Burke": typescript, undated (Box 9)
      - "An Interview with Edmund White by Sam Staggs": typescript, photocopy, undated (Box 9)
      - "Interview with Juan Goytisolo": The New Statesman, article, 1987 October 16 (Box 9)
      - "Interview with Peter Carey": article typescript, undated (Box 9)
      - "Introduction to Dreamers: Drawings by Mel Odom": catalogue, 1984 (Box 9)
      - "Introduction": Collected Novels, by W. M. Spackman, photocopy, undated (Box 9)
      - "Introduction" to A Prisoner of Love by Jean Genet: typescript, photocopy, undated (Box 9)
      - "The Irresponsible Art of Robert Mapplethorpe": The Sentinel, essay, 1980 September 5 (Box 9)
      - "Istanbul: Turkish Delight": typescript, article, undated (Box 9)
      - "James Merrill": essay, American Poetry Review, 1979 September-October (Box 9)
      - "James Schuyler": article, typescript, undated (Box 9)
      - "James Schuyler": Christopher Street, article, 1980 May (Box 9)
      - "James Schuyler": Little Caesar 12, article, 1981 (Box 9)
      - "Jargon": essay, holograph, undated (Box 9)
      - "Jasper Johns and Samuel Beckett": Christopher Street, article, 1977 October (Box 9)
      - "Jasper Johns: Enigmas and Double Visions": Horizon, article, 1977 October (Box 9)
      - "Jean Cocteau": article, proofs, 1984 March 15 (Box 9)
      - Jean Genet
        - Proposal, typescript, undated (Box 9)
        - Notes, holograph, undated (Box 9)
      - "Jean Genet's Prisoner of Love ": Brick 36, essay, 1989 (Box 9)
      - "Jinn City": article, Condé Nast Traveler, 1989 February (Box 9)
      - "John Ashbery": article, Bookletter, 1976 May 24 (Box 9)
      - "Jorge Luis Borges": essay, NOS, 1989 Jun 29 (Box 9)
      - Joy of Gay Sex: book
        - Contract, 1977 Mar 4 (Box 9)
        - Review: Christopher Street, 1977 December (Box 9)
      - "Joyce Baronio": notes, holograph, 1979 (Box 9)
      - "Joyce Baronio on 42nd Street": Village Voice, article, 1979 August 6 (Box 9)
      - "Keith Vaughan: the One-Man Band": article, typescript, 1989 November 7 (Box 9)
      - "Kevin": short story, First Hand, 1983 October (Box 9)
      - "King Farouk Slept Here": Condé Nast Traveler, article, 1987 November (Box 9)
      - "Kundera à la Mode": article, Nation, 1984 May 12 (Box 9)
      - "The Language of Freedom": article, typescript, undated (Box 9)
      - Lecture notes: holograph, undated; 5 (Box 9)
      - Lecture notes: holograph, undated; 4 (Box 10)
      - Leora: musical, typescript, photocopy, undated (Box 10)
      - "Leora Stewart, Fiber Artist": Christopher Street, article, 1980 February (Box 10)
      - "Letter from Paris": article, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 10)
      - "The Library without Walls": Shenandoah 33:3, article, 1982 (Box 10)
      - Like People in History: novel
        - Holograph, 1974 (Box 10)
        - Typescript, 1975; 4 (Box 10)
        - Typescript, corrected, undated; 3 (Box 10)
      - "Logos and Tao": essay, typescript, 1961 January 17 (Box 10)
      - "Los Angeles": Christopher Street, essay, 1978 October (Box 10)
      - "Madame Steiner," play, typescript, 1962-1965 (Box 10)
      - "Man and Woman:" article
        - Holograph, undated (Box 10)
        - Typescript, 1988 September 29 (Box 10)
      - "Man and Woman: Man Ray": Details, article, 1988 (Box 10)
      - "Marilyn et Fred": short story, unidentified magazine clipping, 1988 (Box 10)
      - "Marrakesh": article, holograph, undated (Box 10)
      - "A Memorial Tribute to David Kalstone": booklet, 1986 September 20 (Box 10)
      - "Miro's Latest Works": Horizon, article, 1977 Jul (Box 10)
      - Mrs. Morrigan: novel
        - Typescript, carbon, [1957?] (Box 10)
      - Mrs. Morrigan: play
        - Notes, holograph, undated (Box 10)
        - Typescript, corrected, undated (Box 10)
        - Typescript, photocopy, undated (Box 11)
        - Mimeograph, undated; 2 (Box 11)
        - Copyright, 1965 September 7 (Box 11)
      - "Mystical Petra": article, typescript, undated (Box 11)
      - "Nabokov": article, Saturday Review, 1973 January (Box 11)
      - "Nabokov: Beyond Parody": essay, The Achievements of Vladimir Nabokov, 1984 (Box 11)
      - "Nabokov's Passion": The New York Review of Books, article, 1984 March 29 (Box 11)
      - "Naples' Mixed Bag:" article, typescript, undated (Box 11)
      - "Nile High": article, Departures, 1985 July (Box 11)
      - "A Nocturne"; "Theater": articles, Christopher Street, 1976 July (Box 11)
      - "A Nocturne: Childhood": Shenandoah 29:3, article, 1978 Spring (Box 11)
      - Nocturnes for the King of Naples: play, outline, typescript, 1963? (Box 11)
      - Nocturnes for the King of Naples: novel
        - Notes, typescript, 1975 (Box 11)
        - Holograph, first draft, 1975 (Box 11)
        - Typescript, photocopy, undated; 3 (Box 11)
        - Typescript, carbon, undated (Box 11)
        - Setting typescript, 1978 (Box 11)
        - Proofs, photocopy, 1978 (Box 11)
        - Corrected proofs, photocopy, 1978 (Box 11)
        - Repros (paste-up), 1978 (Box 11)
        - Mechanicals, photocopy, 1978 (Box 11)
        - Extra type, photocopy, undated (Box 11)
        - Contract, 1978 February 16 (Box 11)
        - Blueboy, 1979 May (Box 11)
        - Reviews, 1978-1983; 6 (Box 12)
      - Notebook: holograph, 1963 (Box 12)